<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts About Engineerings on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/posts-about-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Posts About Engineerings on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 10:43:53 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/posts-about-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Finance</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/posts-about-engineering/20240109_google_finance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 10:43:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/posts-about-engineering/20240109_google_finance/</guid><description>So Google Finance is pretty cool. It’s integrated into Google Sheets such that you can get live and historic market data through sheet formulas and the data automatically populates within the Google Sheets. The syntax is:
GOOGLEFINANCE(ticker, [attribute], [start_date], [end_date|num_days], [interval]) I just tried executing the command: =GOOGLEFINANCE(“MES”, “price”, DATE(2023,1,1), DATE(2023,12,31)) and got the historic Micro E-mini S&amp;amp;P 500 Index Futures for 2023:
The only thing that I think could be improved upon would be to get multiple attributes in tabular form with one command.</description></item><item><title>Airflow Documentation</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/posts-about-engineering/20231221_airflow_documentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 18:31:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/posts-about-engineering/20231221_airflow_documentation/</guid><description>These notes are taken from the official Apache Airflow website Documentation section. Will possibly need to reference these notes later. &amp;ldquo;Apache Airflow is an open source platform for developing, scheduling, and monitoring batch-oriented workflows. Airflow’s extensible Python framework enables you to build workflows connecting with virtually any technology. A web interface helps manage the state of your workflows. Airflow is deployable in many ways, varying from a single process on your laptop to a distributed setup to support even the biggest workflows.</description></item></channel></rss>