<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal Thought Posts on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Personal Thought Posts on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:21:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Personal Thought: Jay Shetty Podcast x Emma Watson</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20251012_emma_watson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:21:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20251012_emma_watson/</guid><description>&lt;div class="youtube-wrapper">
 &lt;iframe
 src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2caQ4j9oohE"
 style="border:0; width:100%; aspect-ratio: 16/9;"
 allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"
 allowfullscreen
 >&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>I listened to the whole 02:38:18 &lt;em>Jay Shetty Podcast&lt;/em> episode with &lt;strong>Emma Watson&lt;/strong> recently. I’m not the biggest fan of &lt;strong>Jay Shetty&lt;/strong> given that I don’t find him to be extremely wise or have really good insights. To be honest, he gives very obvious advice in my opinion; he seems more like a new-age guru who makes people feel good as opposed to having true wisdom or truly deep insights. With that said, I do give Jay credit in that he’s a good conversationalist and asks good questions. He does have lots of famous friends and is good at networking and growing his platform. This episode was very interesting because of who the guest was: &lt;strong>Emma Watson&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Personal Thought: On Having Style</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250927_pt_style/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 02:56:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250927_pt_style/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think having &lt;strong>personal style&lt;/strong> is one of the most important things as a person, especially as a creator or a creative person. Having style is something that is not taught in school or in formal education. Yet when someone has style, you know it immediately when you see it. It’s mysterious, unique, and ethereal, but totally present when it’s the real deal. Being stylish can come in many forms, even though it’s often attributed to how one dresses. Beyond just fashion, style can be expressed in how a person speaks, thinks, moves, writes, builds, etc. Moreover, being very good at one’s vocation and doing things that others can’t do is one of the best ways to have a personal style or as they say in business lingo “having a brand.” This is something that I have over the course of my life gained a lot of experience with. For me it’s always been most important to &lt;strong>express myself&lt;/strong>, because I want my true authentic self being put out into the world. It’s often not easy and you suffer from judgement and others’ misunderstandings, but that’s the price to pay for being a trendsetter. Here are five lessons on how to develop your own unique style in whatever that you do:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Personal Thought: On Finding a Passion</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250817_pt_passion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 01:49:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250817_pt_passion/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a topic that I have strong opinions on and it’s something that I’ve ruminated and experimented with for the past ~10 years. I’m not an expert, but I do have some insights as to how this works. One of my biggest fears when I was younger was always this: I was deeply fearful I would not find something that I would be deeply passionate about by the time I turned 30. My worst nightmare would have been doing a job that I had absolutely no passion for; to just go through the motions everyday seemed like a complete nightmare to me. This one fear pervaded my mind for many, many years. I knew who I wanted to be and I was inspired by people who derive great joy in what they do. You notice the difference: the people who love what they do are willing to sacrifice pretty much everything to make their dreams come true. They bring high energy to what they do each and every day. You can feel it, see it, and smell it. I thought given that we spend most of our lives working, it would be totally foolish not to find what my calling was.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Personal Thought: On Failing</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250802_pt_failing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 11:51:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250802_pt_failing/</guid><description>&lt;p>It sucks when you try things and they don’t work out. Just super frustrating when you do things and they don’t turn out to be what you expect or you can’t get it to work. I tried to build three different projects in my spare time this year and none have turned out the way that I thought they would. I just felt like the output was not good enough, so I decided to archive each project and move on to new projects. It’s always exciting to start something new; the beginning is so fun! And then you hit turbulence and roadblocks. You try, try, try and then realize the &lt;strong>sunk-cost fallacy&lt;/strong> is way too overwhelming to continue. You abandon the project in the middle and it never really finishes or is in a state that makes it presentable.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>