<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal Thought Posts on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Personal Thought Posts on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 01:49:39 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Personal Thought: On Finding a Passion</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250817_pt_passion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 01:49:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250817_pt_passion/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a topic that I have strong opinions on and it’s something that I’ve ruminated and experimented with for the past ~10 years. I’m not an expert, but I do have some insights as to how this works. One of my biggest fears when I was younger was always this: I was deeply fearful I would not find something that I would be deeply passionate about by the time I turned 30. My worst nightmare would have been doing a job that I had absolutely no passion for; to just go through the motions everyday seemed like a complete nightmare to me. This one fear pervaded my mind for many, many years. I knew who I wanted to be and I was inspired by people who derive great joy in what they do. You notice the difference: the people who love what they do are willing to sacrifice pretty much everything to make their dreams come true. They bring high energy to what they do each and every day. You can feel it, see it, and smell it. I thought given that we spend most of our lives working, it would be totally foolish not to find what my calling was.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Personal Thought: On Failing</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250802_pt_failing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 11:51:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/personal-thought-posts/20250802_pt_failing/</guid><description>&lt;p>It sucks when you try things and they don’t work out. Just super frustrating when you do things and they don’t turn out to be what you expect or you can’t get it to work. I tried to build three different projects in my spare time this year and none have turned out the way that I thought they would. I just felt like the output was not good enough, so I decided to archive each project and move on to new projects. It’s always exciting to start something new; the beginning is so fun! And then you hit turbulence and roadblocks. You try, try, try and then realize the &lt;strong>sunk-cost fallacy&lt;/strong> is way too overwhelming to continue. You abandon the project in the middle and it never really finishes or is in a state that makes it presentable.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>