<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 21:53:38 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Review: The Commanding Heights (2002 Documentary)</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/finance-posts/20231225_commanding_heights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 21:53:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/finance-posts/20231225_commanding_heights/</guid><description>I just finished watching a documentary series from 2002 called The Commanding Heights based on the book by Daniel Yergin and Joseph Stanislaw. This was a really interesting documentary series that I first learned about from an article on the personal finance website Investopedia. This documentary series is a three-part series that goes through the history of economics from it&amp;rsquo;s foundation to present day (i.e. the 21st century). Yes, the documentary is super dated because it came out in 2002; I could tell that it was pretty dated because of the music, the advertisements shown, and the people who were interviewed.</description></item><item><title>Hugo Reference</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/hugo-reference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 19:23:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/hugo-reference/</guid><description> This is how you create a link to Yahoo. This is how you link image in the static directory. This is an important command: hugo --cleanDestinationDir.</description></item><item><title>Airflow Documentation</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/technology-posts/airflow-documentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 18:31:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/technology-posts/airflow-documentation/</guid><description>These notes are taken from the official Apache Airflow website Documentation section. Will possibly need to reference these notes later. &amp;ldquo;Apache Airflow is an open source platform for developing, scheduling, and monitoring batch-oriented workflows. Airflow’s extensible Python framework enables you to build workflows connecting with virtually any technology. A web interface helps manage the state of your workflows. Airflow is deployable in many ways, varying from a single process on your laptop to a distributed setup to support even the biggest workflows.</description></item></channel></rss>