<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engineering Posts on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/engineering-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Engineering Posts on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:11:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/engineering-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: The Coming Wave</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/engineering-posts/20241215_br_the_coming_wave/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:11:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/engineering-posts/20241215_br_the_coming_wave/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20241215_BR_The_Coming_Wave/cover.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just finished reading &lt;strong>Mustafa Suleyman&lt;/strong>’s book &lt;em>The Coming Wave&lt;/em>. This book I got for free at The Atlantic Festival 2023. My friend told me about the festival last year and I was unsure if going to this event was worth my time or not. But because I had just finished my M.S. degree and was technically still classified as a student, I was able to get the student discount for I think $23. This was a total steal and a great deal, so I thought why not? Why not go to The Atlantic Festival and see what happens? One of the sessions I attended was a panel discussion with supermodel Karlie Kloss and Mustafa Suleyman, co-founder of DeepMind, Infection AI and author of this book; interestingly Mustafa is now at Microsoft and works for Microsoft AI. To be honest, I don’t remember much from their panel discussion. I remember the panel discussion was around noon time and I fell asleep during parts of the discussion. At the end of the discussion, they gave everyone a free copy of Mustafa’s latest book &lt;em>The Coming Wave&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Book Review: Elon Musk</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/engineering-posts/20240902_br_elon_musk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 22:41:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/engineering-posts/20240902_br_elon_musk/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240902_BR_Elon_Musk/cover.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Adversity shaped me,” he (Musk) says. “My pain threshold become very high.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I just finished reading the Walter Isaacson biography: &lt;em>Elon Musk&lt;/em>. My honest review of the book is that it’s ok. It’s not bad, not good; it’s average and I would rate it 2.5/5. I first read Ashlee Vance’s book: &lt;em>Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future&lt;/em> back in 2015, and that was absolutely fantastic. Back then ~10 years ago, Elon Musk was still not well known in terms of his background and career to the general public. Elon was still kind of a mystery, and not the same Elon Musk that we know today. The Walter Isaacson book goes over Elon’s journey from childhood in South Africa to the end of 2022, when he bought Twitter and rebranded it as X.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>