<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cool Event Posts on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Cool Event Posts on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 22:54:50 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Summer Soirée at the French Embassy! 🇫🇷</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240702_french_embassy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 22:54:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240702_french_embassy/</guid><description>So I recently went to Fête de la Musique (World Music Day) at the French Embassy in Georgetown, Washington D.C. I went with a friend and had no idea what to expect! I almost didn’t go because I had no idea what kind of music they were going to play at the event. All I knew was that there was no entrance fee, which is a rarity for an embassy event.</description></item><item><title>Conference Review: PyCon US 2024 (Pittsburgh)</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240606_pycon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 16:14:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240606_pycon/</guid><description>This was the first time I attended PyCon. I was originally slated to go to PyCon in the year 2020 also in Pittsburgh, but the pandemic disrupted the conference (I had the hotel and conference ticket booked at the time). I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to attend PyCon and have been a Python user since I was 18. At PyCon, I was most surprised by the amount of people from all over the world who are Python developers!</description></item><item><title>Volunteering at McKinley Technology High School</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240130_volunteering_mths/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 18:11:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240130_volunteering_mths/</guid><description>Update (Sat. 3/17/24 @ 1:48 AM EST): I’m writing to give an update on my experiences volunteering at McKinley Technology High School in NE, Washington D.C. I’m also attaching a more recent picture of the robot! It is now a fully functioning robot. Overall it’s been a great experience and I’ve learned so much from the students. I would 100% become a volunteer again (if time avails). I’ve tried to add value to what the student’s have been doing with the robot.</description></item></channel></rss>