<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cool Event Posts on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Cool Event Posts on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 23:17:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hosting a Meetup</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240927_hosting_a_meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 23:17:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240927_hosting_a_meetup/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240927_Hosting_A_Meetup/meetup.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed helping host the &lt;em>Launching a Data Science Career&lt;/em> 🚀 panel discussion in collaboration with &lt;strong>Bethesda Data Science&lt;/strong>. It was a good meetup that the team hoped would help people with navigating their careers at the entry-level, mid-level and director level. I just felt that with the current economy the way that it is, there’s so much negativity and hopelessness. There are so many people who are hurting right now due to the fact that they can’t find employment. I, along with the Bethesda Data Science team, wanted to do something about it. We wanted to let people know that there are others out there that care about them. We wanted to give people the chance to ask questions and have their questions answered with specifics. We wanted to give people practical tips that they could implement right away. We don’t know if this meetup helped people at all, but we did everything that we could to put out a meetup worthy of peoples’ time and respect. We prepared questions in advance, had the panelists prepare answers in advance, and there was a lot of communication to make sure the event was a success. There was a high RSVP number and we expected a big turnout. However, around one hour before the event, there was inclement weather in the form of a thunderstorm. The thunderstorm turned out to be not that serious, but it dampened the audience turnout. But hey, it happens! The show must go on, and it did. We ended up doing the meetup and it was a total success. Thanks to the panelists for speaking and &lt;strong>Applied Photons&lt;/strong> for hosting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brave New Voices International Youth Poetry Slam (Finals, 2024)</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240810_brave_new_voices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 08:23:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240810_brave_new_voices/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240810_Brave_New_Voices/brave_new_voices.jpg" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been a fan of poetry for many years now. I was interested in poetry as a young person, and that has carried over into adulthood. I was lucky enough that my teachers in elementary and middle school made us read poetry, and that has sparked an unending fascination with written words and literature to this day. To my surprise, I was so happy to learn that the &lt;strong>Brave New Voices International Youth Poetry Slam (2024)&lt;/strong> was held in D.C. this year! I immediately got a ticket and just knew that I had to be there in-person at the competition finals. Brave New Voices is a nonprofit organization that promotes spoken word poetry, also known as slam poetry for middle school and high school students. It is electric, passionate, and a true art. The poem that I saw ~10 years ago that introduced me to Brave New Voices was a poem called &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P0QiFy8dmX0&amp;amp;t=61s">&lt;strong>Thinking About You&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> (click to view). It is still one of the most creative, unique, and unforgettable poems I have EVER HEARD! I wanted to go to the competition finals to get a better understanding of young people these days and the problems that affect them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fútbol with Spaniards 🇪🇸 and Argentinians 🇦🇷</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240720_futbol/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 12:15:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240720_futbol/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last weekend I went to watch the &lt;em>UEFA Euro Championship 2024&lt;/em> final at Wunder Garten and &lt;em>Copa América 2024&lt;/em> final (unexpectedly) at Lunas de Buenos Aires. I will discuss both events in detail. Soccer (or football to the world) was my first sport and my first love. It’s been years since I’ve played or watched soccer, probably close to 10 years. However, I want to get back into following the sport and possibly even play again. It’s a good way to stay fit and active. Here’s what happened last Sunday (7/14/24) given that there were two major tournament finals happening at the same time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Summer Soirée at the French Embassy! 🇫🇷</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240702_french_embassy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 22:54:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240702_french_embassy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240702_French_Embassy/party.jpg" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I recently went to &lt;strong>Fête de la Musique&lt;/strong> (World Music Day) at the French Embassy in Georgetown, Washington D.C. I went with a friend and had no idea what to expect! I almost didn’t go because I had no idea what kind of music they were going to play at the event. All I knew was that there was no entrance fee, which is a rarity for an embassy event. To be honest, this was the main driving force behind why I wanted to go: it was free and I had never been to the French Embassy before.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Conference Review: PyCon US 2024 (Pittsburgh)</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240606_pycon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 16:14:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240606_pycon/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240606_PyCon/standing.jpg" alt="p1">
&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240606_PyCon/pittsburgh.jpg" alt="p2">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was the first time I attended PyCon. I was originally slated to go to PyCon in the year 2020 also in Pittsburgh, but the pandemic disrupted the conference (I had the hotel and conference ticket booked at the time). I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to attend PyCon and have been a Python user since I was 18. At PyCon, I was most surprised by the amount of people from all over the world who are Python developers! For example I met developers from Norway and Zimbabwe, which are two countries that I’ve never met people from. I really enjoyed some of the talks and some of the notable ones that stood out to me were:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Volunteering at McKinley Technology High School</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240130_volunteering_mths/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 18:11:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/cool-event-posts/20240130_volunteering_mths/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240130_Volunteering_MTHS/robot1.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update (Sat. 3/17/24 @ 1:48 AM EST)&lt;/strong>: I’m writing to give an update on my experiences volunteering at &lt;strong>McKinley Technology High School&lt;/strong> in NE, Washington D.C. I’m also attaching a more recent picture of the robot! It is now a fully functioning robot. Overall it’s been a great experience and I’ve learned so much from the students. I would 100% become a volunteer again (if time avails). I’ve tried to add value to what the student’s have been doing with the robot. But the reality of the situation is that I’ve learned more from them than they’ve learned from me. I never had the opportunities that the students have at McKinley when I was a young person; therefore, it has made me so happy to help support them. I want to update the post because there are some key lessons that I want to remember forever from my experiences at McKinley:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>