<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social Science Posts on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Social Science Posts on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:58:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: Crucial Conversations</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/20251218_br_crucial_conversations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:58:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/20251218_br_crucial_conversations/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20251219_BR_Crucial_Conversations/cover.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I finished reading the famous book on communication &lt;strong>Crucial Conversations&lt;/strong> a few months ago this year. &lt;em>Crucial Conversations&lt;/em> offers advice on how to deal with high stakes conversations in a business and work context. At the same time the advice can be applied to all areas of communication, including at home and in our personal lives. I read the first edition of the book that was published back in 2002 (found it online for free). As a strong communicator myself, this book has only sharpened my communication skills and taken my skills to the next level. I’ve had years of experience honing my communication skills and am always learning and trying to be better. This book is old but still very popular; I definitely got what I wanted from the first edition and am satisfied with the lessons learned. The book was a strong book overall and offers some frameworks that one can apply in day-to-day life. Here are the four frameworks within the book &lt;em>Crucial Conversations&lt;/em> that I love the most:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Book Review: How to Talk to Anyone</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/20250628_br_talk_to_anyone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 16:25:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/20250628_br_talk_to_anyone/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20250628_BR_Talk_To_Anyone/cover.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just finished reading &lt;strong>How to Talk to Anyone - 92 Little Tricks for Big Success in Relationships&lt;/strong> by &lt;strong>Leil Lowndes&lt;/strong>. This is a fantastic book that teaches one how to approach business networking as both a science and an art. This book has some true gems when it comes to what to say and do in work, business, and other social settings. The author Leil Lowndes clearly has years of experience when it comes to wielding a strong social game and she has great wisdom. I’ve been to countless meetups, conferences, talks, company events, and business soirées in the past 10 years and thought of myself as a strong networker. I realized from reading this book that there’s another level and I’ve gained new insights that I never thought of before. I’ve gained new ideas and new things to try out next time and I believe these new skills will take my networking abilities to the next level. What I appreciated most about this book is that it’s very practical in nature. A lot of the ideas you can implement right away. Therefore, I’m going to share the five tricks that I found most insightful from a truly excellent book!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>