<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social Science Posts on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Social Science Posts on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 16:25:35 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: How to Talk to Anyone</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/20250628_br_talk_to_anyone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 16:25:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/social-science-posts/20250628_br_talk_to_anyone/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20250628_BR_Talk_To_Anyone/cover.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just finished reading &lt;strong>How to Talk to Anyone - 92 Little Tricks for Big Success in Relationships&lt;/strong> by &lt;strong>Leil Lowndes&lt;/strong>. This is a fantastic book that teaches one how to approach business networking as both a science and an art. This book has some true gems when it comes to what to say and do in work, business, and other social settings. The author Leil Lowndes clearly has years of experience when it comes to wielding a strong social game and she has great wisdom. I’ve been to countless meetups, conferences, talks, company events, and business soirées in the past 10 years and thought of myself as a strong networker. I realized from reading this book that there’s another level and I’ve gained new insights that I never thought of before. I’ve gained new ideas and new things to try out next time and I believe these new skills will take my networking abilities to the next level. What I appreciated most about this book is that it’s very practical in nature. A lot of the ideas you can implement right away. Therefore, I’m going to share the five tricks that I found most insightful from a truly excellent book!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>