<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Economics and Finance Posts on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Economics and Finance Posts on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:55:50 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: Basic Economics</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/20240507_br_basic_economics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:55:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/20240507_br_basic_economics/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240507_BR_Basic_Economics/cover.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a long overdue blog post about the book &lt;strong>Basic Economics; A Citizen’s Guide to the Economy&lt;/strong> written by &lt;em>Dr. Thomas Sowell&lt;/em>. Dr. Sowell is a world-renowned economist who has had an amazing academic career. He is a proponent of the Chicago School of Economics, which is a &lt;strong>neoclassical school&lt;/strong> of thought that has full confidence in a free market, price-coordinated economy. This was honestly an eye-opening book that has a vast amount of knowledge if one were to read the book carefully. The book is pretty high-level and conceptual, but the implications are practical in nature (i.e. you can actually apply some of the theory in real life). The book really lifts the lid on how capitalism works under the hood, both its virtues and its flaws. No system is perfect, but Dr. Sowell argues that the free market system will always be better than any other system. Here are the top five lessons that I learned from &lt;strong>Basic Economics&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Book Review: A Random Walk Down Wall St.</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/20240316_br_a_random_walk_down_wall_st/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/20240316_br_a_random_walk_down_wall_st/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240317_BR_A_Random_Down_Wall_St/cover.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240317_BR_A_Random_Down_Wall_St/malkiel.png" alt="p2">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just finished reading the classic book on personal finance and investing, &lt;strong>A Random Walk Down Wall St.&lt;/strong> written by &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burton_Malkiel">Dr. Burton Malkiel&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> (Professor Emeritus at Princeton U. Economics). It&amp;rsquo;s been said that Dr. Malkiel has the common sense of &lt;em>Benjamin Franklin&lt;/em>, the academic/institutional knowledge of &lt;em>Dr. Milton Friedman&lt;/em> and the practical experience of &lt;em>Warren Buffett&lt;/em>. His investment advice is considered by the Wall St. Journal to be &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>the best and latest investment advice money can buy&lt;/em>.&amp;rdquo; I’m really happy I finally finished reading this book. I tried reading it for the first time back in 2016 and was not able to do so. At the time, the book was way too advanced for me and I didn’t have the background knowledge to be able to really understand it at a deep level. However over the years, I’ve learned more about finance to the point where I now feel confident when it comes to topics such as saving for retirement, investing in securities, personal finance, etc. I was so happy with finishing the book that I wrote to Dr. Malkiel at his Princeton email address and he responded! I will cherish this memory forever and will always thank Dr. Malkiel for the knowledge that he imparted with me through his book. Here are the top five lessons that I learned from &lt;strong>A Random Walk Down Wall St.&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Book Review: Titan</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/20240130_br_titan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 16:59:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/20240130_br_titan/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20240130_BR_Titan/cover.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I just finished reading the book &lt;strong>Titan&lt;/strong> by &lt;em>Ron Chernow&lt;/em>. This book was a total tomb! It took me close to a year to crawl through the whole book; I thought at one point that I was never going to finish reading the book! I first held a copy of the book years ago at a friend&amp;rsquo;s apartment and I was always fascinated to learn more about &lt;strong>John D. Rockefeller Sr.&lt;/strong>, who many people consider America’s first billionaire. However, the reality is that Rockfeller never reached one billion dollars net worth in his life; rather at its height, Rockefeller had a net worth of +$900M USD. Regardless of technicalities, this kind of money in the late 19th and early 20th century was unprecedented and his story is a rather crazy one. Born into a broken family, Rockefeller had to leave school at age 16 with a half finished high school education and go work to support himself and his siblings. From working jobs in his youth, to starting his own commodities trading enterprise, to getting into the oil refining business at the right time, this book was the story of a great life. Here are the five biggest lessons I learned from the richest American (adjusted for inflation) of all time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Documentary Review: The Commanding Heights (2002 Documentary)</title><link>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/20231225_commanding_heights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 21:53:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yli12313.github.io/blog/economics-and-finance-posts/20231225_commanding_heights/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yli12313.github.io/blog/blog/20231225_Commanding_Heights/title.png" alt="p1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just finished watching a documentary series from 2002 called &lt;strong>The Commanding Heights&lt;/strong> based on the book by &lt;em>Daniel Yergin&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Joseph Stanislaw&lt;/em>. This was a really interesting documentary series that I first learned about from an article on the personal finance website &lt;a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/professionals/100215/10-must-watch-documentaries-finance-professionals.asp">Investopedia&lt;/a>. This documentary series is a three-part series that goes through the history of economics from it&amp;rsquo;s foundation to present day (i.e. the 21st century). Yes, the documentary is super dated because it came out in 2002; I could tell that it was pretty dated because of the music, the advertisements shown, and the people who were interviewed. However, sometimes we can learn a lot from the past and this documentary series is really educational for anyone interested in learning more about economics and global finance. I will summarize my key learnings from each part of the documentary right here.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>